Dr. Jiangshan Yu (BE, MSc, MPhil, PhD)

CONTACT INFORMATION

Room C024,

Weicker Building,

University of Luxembourg,

L-2721, Luxembourg.

E-mail:

j.yu.research@gmail.com

Home-page:

www.jiangshanyu.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS My research interests are in **cyber security and user privacy**. In particular, the focus of my research has been on applied crypto, secure authentication, key management, public key infrastructure, secure messaging, post-compromise security, and formal se-

curity verification.

EDUCATION

Ph.D in Cyber Security, Oct.2012-Sept.2016. **University of Birmingham**, UK.

Thesis: Mitigating private key compromise.

M.Phil in Cryptography (2011-2012). University of Wollongong, NSW, Australia.

Thesis: Remote User Authentication in Distributed Systems and Networks.

M.Sc. in Information Security (2010-2011). University of Wollongong, Australia.

B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology (2005-2009), Northeast Agricultural

University, Harbin, China. (Top 1 out of 82, Best Thesis Award).

POSITIONS

Research fellow, Interdisciplinary Centre for Security, Reliability and Trust (SnT), University of Luxembourg, Luxembourg. (2016-Present)

Honorary research fellow, University of Birmingham, UK. (2016-Present)

Director, CloudTomo Limited, UK. (2014-2016)

Tech consultant, Jin Xin Tong Trust and Investment Corporation Ltd, UK. (2014-2015)

President, Endless Martial Arts Association, Wollongong, Australia. (2011-2012)

Manager, Department of Student Service, Wollongong Chinese Students & Scholars Association, Wollongong, NSW, Australia.(2010-2012)

President, Guild of Students, Northeast Agricultural University. (2007-2009)

SELECTED PROJECTS:

Co-Designer. Huawei SoC Secure Boot Solution, UK. 2016. (Funded by Huawei Ltd.)

Project manager. Innovate UK project on user-friendly security and privacy to increase confidence in cloud-based systems, UK. June - September, 2015. (Funded by

Innovate UK.)

GRANT:

"Technology inspired feasibility study for secure email and cloud storage", GBP33,000 from Technology Strategy Board (Innovate UK), 2015.

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES:

(Finalist) RAEng Enterprise Fellowship, Royal Academy of Engineering, UK. 2015.

Chair, *The future of digital currency and block chain technology workshop*, Birmingham, UK. September, 2015.

PC member, Software Architecture for Big Data and the Cloud, 2016.

Invited Reviewer (Journal):

• IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics & Security; The Computer Journal; Journal of Information Security and Applications; Security and Communication Networks; International Journal of Information Security.

Invited Reviewer (Conference):

 ACISP 2013; ESORICS 2013; DPM 2013; ACNS 2014; SEC 2014; FMS 2014; WPES 2014; POST (ETAPS) 2015; ASIACCS 2015; IFIP SEC 2015; IEEE Euro S&P 2016; ESSoS 2016; IFIP SEC 2016; ESORICS 2016; WISTP 2016; EuroSys 2017; AsiaCCS 2017.

PATENTS Key Usage Detection (Patent pending)

- UK Patent Application GB 1416188.9
- US Patent Application US 14/852,342

AWARDS Scholarships:

- Universitas 21 scholarship from the University of Birmingham, 2015.
- EPSRC project funding for PhD studies at University of Birmingham, 2012 2015.
- Overseas top-up scholarship from the University of Birmingham for PhD studies, 2012 - 2015.
- First class scholarship, Northeast Agricultural University, Harbin, Heilongjiang, China, 2006, 2007, and 2008.

Other:

- **First place award**, the Coniston poster competition, University of Birmingham, UK, 2014.
- Outstanding Graduates of Heilongjiang Province, Heilongjiang, China, 2009;
- Outstanding Graduates of Northeast Agricultural University, Harbin, Heilongjiang, China, 2009;
- Best Undergraduate Thesis Award, Northeast Agricultural University, Harbin, Heilongjiang, China, 2009;
- Outstanding Academic Award, The Northeast Agricultural University, China, 2008;
- First National Prize of China Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling, China, 2007;
- **Second National Prize** of China Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling, China, 2006;
- Outstanding Student Award of The Northeast Agricultural University, China, 2006;
- Outstanding Student Leadership Award, The Northeast Agricultural University, China, 2006.